Guide to the Stanford University, Libraries, Department of Special Collections and University Archives, Records SC0756
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Manuscript Division Reference Files, circa 1960s-1990s; Accession ARCH_2011_073; 7.5 Linear Feet; (5 boxes)
  - Alaska Commercial Company (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Allingham (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Authors (M122) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American History Collection (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - American West (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ames Family (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Amundsen, Roald (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Anderson Family Papers (M51, M111, M171, M243) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Anderson, Sherwood (M122, M143) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Anthony, Susan B. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Apple Computer Collection (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Arabic Mss (M69) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Artists (M136) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Artotypes (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Atherton, Gertrude (M206) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Atkinson, William L. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Augustine (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Austen, Jane (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Austrian Newspaper Collection (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - B - Miscellaneous Reference (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Baca (M890) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bacon (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Baldwin Locomotive Works (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Barnes (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Barnet-Sanchez/Sanchex-Tranquilino Papers (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Baseball (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Baron (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Beckman (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bell, John R. (M63) (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bender, Albert M. (M25, various sources) (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Beneventan Fragment (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Benson, E. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bernstein Fragments (M299) (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Beswich Collection - correspondence re: (M361) (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Bierce, Ambrose Gwinnet (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Bierce, Ambrose Gwinnet (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Biosystematicists (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Bishop, Elizabeth (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Black History (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Bliss fragment (M389) (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Bolinger, Dwight (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Bliven, Bruce (M236, M1, M16, M122, M203) (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Boggs, William (M67) (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Bolitho, Hector (Isobel Field) (M41) (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Borel Collection, The - California History (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Born (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Bowles, Paul (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Bradford, J. O. (M46) (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Brasch Collection (M176) (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Brasch - Newton (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Brandeis, L. D. (M2) (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Brandt, K. (M1) (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - British Authors (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - British Mss - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck (M1, M16, M52, M122) (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Browning, Elizabeth B. (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Browning, R. (M121) (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Bryan, W J. (M215) (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Buck, Pearl (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Bull, R. (M18) (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Bunau - Varilla, P. (M96) (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Burke, Edmund (M129) (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Burr, Aaron (M1, M104) (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Butler, Phyllis (M266) (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Butterworth (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Bynner, Witter (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - C- Miscellaneous Reference (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Cable Cars (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Caddes, Carolyn (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - California Historical Sources (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - California Missions (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - California Women Gold Rush (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - California and Western Manuscripts (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Caligraphy (Jung Collector) (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Cara Exhibition (M666) (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Carleton, J. H. Gold Rush (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Carman, Bliss (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Carmichael, Stokely (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Carnegie, Andrew (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - CASA Reference Requests (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cassals, Pablo (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cassirer (M287) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cather, Willa (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cator, T.V. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cavendish, G. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Central Pacific Railroad Co. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chandos Magazine (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chicano Studies Collection (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Chicano Studies Collection (general reference inquiries) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Childhood (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Chinese (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Chit Chat Club (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Christie, J.B. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Church, Frank (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Civil Rights (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Civil War (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Clark, George (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Clemens, Cyril (1, 122, 190) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Clemens, Samuel (Mark Twain) (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Clendenen (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cobden - Sanderson (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Coleman, Wm. T. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Coleridge, S. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Collections - Spurious (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Collins, Tom (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Collins, W. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Colonial Mss. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Colt Press (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Compton-Burnett (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Congressional Members, collections relating to (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Conrad, Joseph (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Cookery (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Corona, Bert (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cortina, Juan (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - County Archives (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Cowell, Henry (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Crane (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Creel, George (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Creeley, Robert (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Crocker Family (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Crockett, David (Doc. Ethel Day) (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Crothers Papers (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Culver, R. K. (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Cunningham, J. V. (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - D - miscellaneous reference (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Darrow, Clarence (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Daves, Delmer (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Davis, Angela (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Davis, Jefferson (2, 210, 191) (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Deal (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Deitrick, James (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Devoto, Bernard - Use 1956-1965 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - DeVoto, Bernard - Use 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - DeVoto, Bernard - Use 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - DeVoto, Bernard - Use 1977-1982 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Devoto Reference (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Dewey, John (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Diaries (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Dickens, Charles (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Dickenson, Dr. R. L. (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Documents, miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Dodge (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Donahoe - Kelly Papers (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Dos Passos (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Doyle, Katherine E. (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Dragmaticon (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Draper, Anne - reference request (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Drieser, Theodore (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Driscoll, Emily (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Dryburgh, Margaret (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Duffus, R. L. (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Duffy, Philip (Bret Harte Letter) (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Dunning, Phillip (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Duret, Theodore (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - E - miscellaneous reference (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - EPIC campaign (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Earthquake, San Francisco, 1906 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Eastern Europe (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Einstein, A. (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Electrical Engineering (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Eliot, T. S. (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Elkins, Kate (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Elwell, Cyril (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Ely, Northcutt (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Emerson, R. W. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Engelbart, Douglas (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - England Western Circuit Court (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - English List reference (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Evans, Wentz (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Exactus Photo-Film Corporation (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Explorations - 19th and 20th Century (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - F - miscellaneous reference (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Facsimiles of Historical Documents (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Fairchild (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Farm Labor (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Foerster, Norman (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Foote, reference inquiries, 1978- (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Foote, reference inquiries, 1961-1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Forbes, Robertson (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Forest History (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Forker, Lloyd and Paul (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Franklin, Benjamin (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Franklin, Howard Bruce (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Fremont, J. C. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - French Manuscripts (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Frost, Robert (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Froude reference (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - G - miscellaneous reference (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Galazrza reference inquiries (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Galsworthy reference (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Gamboa (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Gardiner (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Gardner, John W. (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Genealogy (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - German Manuscripts (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Gessner, Conrad (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Gibbon, Edward (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Gibbons correspondence (both James and A. C. Gibbons) (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Gifford, Barry (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Ginsberg, Allen (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Gioia, Dana (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Gissing (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Goddard, George W., reference (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Godel, Kurt, papers (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Goethe (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Gordon (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Grant, U. S. (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Greene, Nathaniel (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Gros reference (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Guerard, Albert L. (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - H - miscellaneous reference (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Hadden, Anne (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Hamilton, Alex (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Handwriting reference (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Hanewacker, xeroxes (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Hanewacker, Civil War (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Hanley Paul (M151) (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Hardy, Irene (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Hardy, Thomas (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Harland, Henry (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Hart photos (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Harte, Bret (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Harwood family (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Hatlo, Jimmy (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Haupt Papers (M356) (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Hawthorne, Nathaniel (M206) (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Healy, James A. (M273) (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Hayes, Rutherford B. (M2) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Heinemann reference file (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Hemingway (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Hemingway reference (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Heney, Francis J. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Henly, W. M. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Herzmanovsky reference (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Higford Family (M586) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hill, Andrew (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Hill, Frank Ernest (M212) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Hilton, Ned (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - History of Science (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Hoover, Herbert (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Hopkins Transportation Library (M97, M200, M234) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Hopkins, Timothy (M36, M97) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Horne, Herbert P. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Howe (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Howell Reference (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Hunecker, James G. (M113) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Huntington, Collis P. (M217, M97) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hutchings, Charles (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Huxley, Aldous (M107) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Hwang, David (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Hyde, William B. (M267) (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - I - miscellaneous reference (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Ibarbourou, Juana de (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Immigration History (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Indians (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Irish, John (M33) (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Irish Literature (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Irving, Washington (M104, M122) (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Islas, Arturo (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - J - miscellaneous reference (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Jackling, D. C. (M93) (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Jacks, David - reference (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Jacks (M68) (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Jackson Library (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Jackson, Andrew (M2, M5, M18) (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - James, William (M36, M130, M206) (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Jeffers, Robinson (M124, M240) (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Jeffreys, D. W. (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Jewish-American (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Jewish Life in the Bay Area (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Johnson, Andrew (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Johnson, Hiram (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Jones (M099, M208) (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Jones, H. C. (M36, AC33b, M99, M208) (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Journals (for class demonstrations) (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Joyce, James (M121) (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - K, miscellaneous reference (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Kadinsky, Francois (M123) (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Kahn, Julius (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Kane, Elizabeth Kent (M61) (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Kane, Thomas L. (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Additional Material, ARCH-2017-304
  Conditions Governing Access
  Materials are restricted from 75 years of creation in the interest of donor privacy.
  - Annual Report - 2 years worth of notable acquisitions, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Contingency Planning Statement, 1995 Oct (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Publications making heavy use of SC, SUL (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Molecular Biology oral history proposal, 1995 Mar (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chemistry Book Collection, 1996 Apr (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - French Engineering - $$ needed, 1996 Mar (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Greenhouse Review Press order, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - WWII Engineering Prints(pot acq) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Atlanta - Nexus Press (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Katherine Pinkham Harris (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Motion Study (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Forms (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Comic Books, 1994 Aug 15 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ginsberg archive, incl. template for contract (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - E. Reid collection of Jack Yeats materials (via Shasky), 1994 Mar 10 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - San Pablo Bible Facsimile (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Smart Valley, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Civil War Diary (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Kane, Thomas L. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Marcus Collection (via Roger Kohn) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Everson "archive" (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - William Morris Collection (Berger) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - KPFA collection, 1994 Mar 7 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Condorcet MSS at Quaritch, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Thiel, K. Potential Donor (Africana) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Dennis Ryan Cartoon Collection, 1995 Mar (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - e-Copyright (Background) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Digital Libraries etc. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Preservation of e-records (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Annual Donor Letters '96, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - ASUL Development Workshop (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - ASUL (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Book Fund Proposals (Draft) (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - OOD (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Sowers, M.-- Durer (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Newsletter "News and notable in Special Collections (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Book Fair Exhibit (SF), 1995 Feb 24-26 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Book fair report (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Sorts Culture - Class + conference (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "Teaching the Far West" exhibit, 1995 Apr (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Mexican-American / Chicano ? (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Judaica / Hebraica HAS curators (pending) (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Germanic Collection (incl. pending) (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - HST Collection [incl pending] (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Maraini, Dacia - pot acq (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Book Arts Conference ? Suzie Duan / Hum Ctr (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - LA Trip, 1995 Mar (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Micro sabbaticals (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Retreat - coll devt, 1994 Apr 20 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Shelf Road Proposal (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Collections - dept. inventory (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Keys - lost keys, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - BAMBAM (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Security - Theft (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Gilroy theft (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Copyright (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - West Stack Inventory (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Maps - West Stacks (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Book Theft 1990 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Venzor (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - James Wilson Mull Case (Sepcial Collections) (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Blumberg Theft (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - PRLDEF /MALDEF NEH 1993 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2018-118
  - Pat White Retirement, 2011 May 28; 1_01; 1 videotape(s) (minidv) (Box 1)
  - Pat White Retirement, 2011 May 28; 1_02; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 1)
  - Pat White Retirement, 2011 May 28; 1_03; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd-rom) (Box 1)